Guide to the Ruth Fulton Benedict Papers, 1857-1958
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1953
  - ORGANIZATIONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - West Side Defense Council, 1942 (Folder 21.8)
    - West Side Defense Council, 1942 (Folder 21.9)
    - West Side Defense Council, 1942 (Folder 21.10)
  - CORRESPONDENCE OF THE JOURNAL OF AMERICAN FOLK-LORE
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1923-1926 (Folder 22.1)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1927 (Folder 22.2)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1928 (Folder 22.3)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1928 (Folder 22.4)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1929 (Folder 22.5)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1930 (Folder 22.6)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1930 (Folder 22.7)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1930 (Folder 22.8)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1930 (Folder 22.9)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1931 (Folder 23.1)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1932 (Folder 23.2)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1932 (Folder 23.3)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1932 (Folder 23.4)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1933 (Folder 23.5)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1933 (Folder 23.6)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1933 (Folder 23.7)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1933 (Folder 23.8)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1933 (Folder 23.9)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1934 (Folder 24.1)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1934 (Folder 24.2)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1934 (Folder 24.3)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1934 (Folder 24.4)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1934 (Folder 24.5)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1935 (Folder 24.6)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1935 (Folder 24.7)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1935 (Folder 24.8)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1936 (Folder 25.1)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1936 (Folder 25.2)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1936 (Folder 25.3)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1936 (Folder 25.4)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1936 (Folder 25.5)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1937 (Folder 25.6)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1938 (Folder 25.7)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1938 (Folder 25.8)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1938 (Folder 25.9)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1938 (Folder 25.10)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1939 (Folder 26.1)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1939 (Folder 26.2)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1940 (Folder 26.3)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1941 (Folder 26.4)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1942 (Folder 26.5)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore, 1944 (Folder 26.6)
    - Journal of American Folk-Lore: Editor's Reports, undated (Folder 26.7)
  - CORRESPONDENCE WITH STUDENTS AND COLLEAGUES
    - Aberle, David Friend, 1942-1948 (Folder 27.1)
    - Ackerknecht, Erwin H., 1942-1947 (Folder 27.2)
    - Adams, Thelma, 1932-1933 (Folder 27.3)
    - Aginsky, Bernard, 1933-1936 (Folder 27.4)
    - Arensberg, Conrad M., undated (Folder 27.5)
    - Ashley-Montagu, Montague Francis See Montagu, Ashley, 1934-1945 (Folder 27.6)
    - Ball, Leona, 1930-1931 (Folder 27.7)
    - Barsky, Jeannette [Mirsky], 1934-1938 (Folder 27.8)
    - Barton, [Roy Franklyn], 1930-1944 (Folder 27.9)
    - Benedict, Ruth Boschwitz, M.D., undated (Folder 27.10)
    - Benet, Sarah "Sula,", 1938-1945 (Folder 27.11)
    - Blumensohn, Jules -- SEE Henry, Jules, undated
    - Bryan, Ruth [Anthropology Dept. secretary?], 1927-1945 (Folder 27.12)
    - Bunzel, Ruth Leah, 1930-1947 (Folder 27.13)
    - Bush, Wendell T., 1928 (Folder 27.14)
    - Carter, Isabel Gordon, 1933-1947 (Folder 27.15)
    - Carter, Isabel Gordon, 1929-1946 (Folder 27.15a)
    - Childs, Gladwyn M., 1931-1943 (Folder 27.16)
    - Cooper, John Montgomery, 1936-1942 (Folder 27.17)
    - D'Angulo, Jaime, 1930-1936 (Folder 28.1)
    - DeLaguna, Frederica, 1933-1942 (Folder 28.2)
    - Deloria, Ella, 1925-1944 (Folder 28.3)
    - Deloria, Ella, 1941-1948 (Folder 28.4)
    - Dollard, John, 1935-1936 (Folder 28.5)
    - DuBois, Cora, 1929-1942 (Folder 28.6)
    - Eglar, Zekiye Suleyman, 1938-1948 (Folder 28.7)
    - Goldenweiser, Alexander A., 1931-1941 (Folder 28.8)
    - Goldfrank, Esther Schiff (Wittfogel), 1939-1940 (Folder 28.9)
    - Goldman, Irving, 1935-1940 (Folder 28.10)
    - Gorer, Geoffrey Edgar, 1936-1947 (Folder 28.11)
    - Hahn-Husemann, Frida K., 1937-1939 (Folder 28.12)
    - Hallowell, Alfred Irving, 1933-1948 (Folder 28.13)
    - Hanks, Jane Richardson, 1940-1942 (Folder 28.14)
    - Harms, Ernst [Director of the Social Sciences], 1941 (Folder 28.15)
    - Harris, Jack, 1936-1941 (Folder 29.1)
    - Harris, Pippa, 1945-1948 (Folder 29.2)
    - Hellersberg, Elisabeth, 1945-1947 (Folder 29.3)
    - Henry, Jules, 1930-1935 (Folder 29.4)
    - Henry, Jules, 1936-1940 (Folder 29.5)
    - Henry, Jules, 1941-1942 (Folder 29.6)
    - Henry, Jules, 1944-1948 (Folder 29.7)
    - Herskovits, Melville Jean, 1930-1940 (Folder 29.8)
    - Herzog, George, 1930-1939 (Folder 29.9)
    - Hu, Hsien Chin, 1941-1946 (Folder 30.1)
    - Huot- Champion, Martha and Louis, 1937-1948 (Folder 30.2)
    - Hurston, Zora Neale, 1932-1945 (Folder 30.3)
    - Hurston, Zora Neale, [undated] (Folder 30.4)
    - Jacobs, Melville, 1935-1943 (Folder 30.5)
    - Joffe, Natalie F., 1939 (Folder 30.6)
    - Kahn, Hannah, 1934-1935 (Folder 30.7)
    - Kardiner, Abram, 1940-1946 (Folder 30.8)
    - Kennard, Edward Allan, 1934-1946 (Folder 30.9)
    - Kingsbury, Susan M., 1941-1947 (Folder 30.10)
    - Kirchhoff, Paul, 1935-1939 (Folder 30.11)
    - Kluckhohn, Clyde Kay Maben, 1938-1948 (Folder 30.12)
    - Kroeber, Alfred Louis, 1928-1947 (Folder 30.13)
    - LaBarre, Weston, 1946-1947 (Folder 31.1)
    - Landes, Ruth Schlossberg, 1932-1933 (Folder 31.2)
    - Landes, Ruth Schlossberg, 1934-1937 (Folder 31.3)
    - Landes, Ruth Schlossberg, 1938-1939 (Folder 31.4)
    - Landes, Ruth Schlossberg, 1940 (Folder 31.5)
    - Lee, Dorothy Demetracopoulou, 1931-1943 (Folder 31.6)
    - Lesser, Alexander, 1930-1943 (Folder 31.7)
    - Lewis, Oscar, 1939-1947 (Folder 31.8)
    - Lincoln, Jackson Steward, 1939-1941 (Folder 31.9)
    - Linton, Ralph, 1932-1943 (Folder 31.10)
    - Lipkind, William, 1931-1939 (Folder 31.11)
    - Lipkind, William, 1940-1946 (Folder 31.12)
    - Lloyd, Wilma, 1947 (Folder 32.1)
    - Loeb, Margery, [1940] (Folder 32.2)
    - Lowie, Robert H., 1922-1929 (Folder 32.3)
    - Lowie, Robert H., 1931-1947 (Folder 32.4)
    - McPhee, Colin, 1937-1938 (Folder 32.5)
    - Malinowski, Bronislaw, 1926-1937 (Folder 32.6)
    - Mandelbaum, May, 1932-1948 (Folder 32.7)
    - Maslow, Abe, 1939-1940 (Folder 32.8)
    - Métraux, Alfred, 1937-1939 (Folder 32.9)
    - Mirsky, Jeannette -- SEE Barsky, Jeannette, undated
    - Mishkin, Bernard, 1934-1944 (Folder 32.10)
    - Ashley, Montagu, 1934-1945 (Folder 27.6)
    - Opler, Marvin Kaufmann, 1933-1935 (Folder 32.11)
    - Opler, Morris Edward, 1936-1940 (Folder 32.12)
    - Opler, Morris Edward, 1936-1947 (Folder 32.13)
    - Opler, Morris Edward -- SEE ALSO Folders 79.9-79.10, undated
    - Parsons, Elsie Clews, 1923-1932 (Folder 33.1)
    - Parsons, Elsie Clews (1874-1941), 1933-1941 (Folder 33.2)
    - Petrullo, Vincenzo, 1947 (Folder 33.3)
    - Porter, Philip S., undated (Folder 33.4)
    - Radin, Paul, 1924-1943 (Folder 33.5)
    - Reichard, Gladys Amanda, 1927-1943 (Folder 33.6)
    - Rodnick, David, 1944-1947 (Folder 33.7)
    - Sapir (Jean and Philip), 1931-1947 (Folder 33.8)
    - Siegel, Morris, 1936-1948 (Folder 33.9)
    - Smith, Marian, 1929-1945 (Folder 34.1)
    - Spitzer, H. M., 1946-1947 (Folder 34.2)
    - Stout, David B., undated (Folder 34.3)
    - Stout, Earl J., 1935-1939 (Folder 34.4)
    - Susman, Amelia, 1937 (Folder 34.5)
    - Tax, Sol, 1931-1940 (Folder 34.6)
    - Tax, Sol — SEE ALSO Folder 79.14, undated
    - Tozzer, Alfred Marston, 1928-1936 (Folder 34.7)
    - Underhill, Ruth, 1933-1946 (Folder 34.8)
    - Underhill, Ruth, 1933-1946 (Folder 34.9)
    - Wagley, Charles William, 1935-1939 (Folder 34.10)
    - Weltfish, Gene Regina, 1928-1937 (Folder 34.11)
    - White, Leslie Alvin, 1931-1943 (Folder 34.12)
    - Whitman, William, 1933-1938 (Folder 34.13)
    - Withers, Carl, 1943-1945 (Folder 34.14)
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Personal Correspondence to/from Benedict, A-K, 1937-1948 (Folder 35.1)
    - Personal Correspondence to/from Benedict, L-W and unidentified, 1934-1946 (Folder 35.2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1934-1947 (Folder 35.3)
    - Literary Correspondence (Léonie Adams; Will Gibson; Ruth Goddard; Rolfe Humphries; Charles Olson; Myra), 1933-1946 (Folder 35.4)
    - Informants' Letters, 1926-1936 (Folder 35.5)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, undated (Folder 35.6)
- SERIES II. DIARIES, BIOGRAPHICAL NOTEBOOKS AND NOTE CARDS, BIOGRAPHICAL AND FAMILY-RELATED MATERIALS, 1912-1952
  - Diary (Fragments), undated (Folder 36.1)
  - Diary (Poetry), 1912 (Folder 36.2)
  - Diary (Poetry), l923, 1925 (Folder 36.3)
  - Diary, 1926 (Folder 37.1)
  - Diary, 1926 (Folder 37.2)
  - Notebook - Washington Diary, undated (Folder 37.3)
  - Autobiographical Notebook, Notes, undated (Folder 37.4)
  - Notebook - Early drafts: poetry, prose, undated (Folder 37.5)
  - Notebook, undated (Folder 37.6)
  - Notes - Comments on Poetry, undated (Folder 37.7)
  - Note Cards [biographical information about RFB gleaned by Marie Eichelberger and others from RFB's professional correspondence and correspondence files on organizations], undated (Box 38)
  - Ruth Fulton Benedict Chronology, undated (Folder 39.1)
  - Fulton-Shattuck Family Tree, undated (Folder 39.2)
  - Ruth Fulton Benedict Biographical Data, undated (Folder 39.3)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical and Autobiographical Notes, undated (Folder 39.4)
  - Awards given to Ruth Benedict, undated (Folder 39.5)
  - Awards given to Ruth Benedict: Illinois Institute of Technology, Institute of Design, Award for Standards of Excellence in A-V Communication, 1952 (Folder 40.1 (Oversize))
  - Awards given to Ruth Benedict: Lord and Taylor Annual American Design Award, 1946 (Folder 40.2 (Oversize))
  - Awards given to Ruth Benedict: National C. I. O. Committee to Abolish Racial Discrimination, Certificate of Recognition, 1944 (Folder 40.3 (Oversize))
  - Ruth Fulton Benedict - Obituaries, undated (Folder 39.6)
  - Ruth Fulton Benedict - Last Will and Testament (2), 1937, 1948 (Folder 39.7)
  - Contents of Benedict's purse at her death, undated (Folder 39.8)
  - Fulton Family Genealogy, undated (Folder 39.9)
  - Correspondence: Margery Freeman [RFB's sister]-Ruth Fulton Benedict[additional letter in folder 39.8], undated (Folder 39.10)
  - Correspondence: Margery Freeman-Auntie My [Myra Shattuck], undated (Folder 39.11)
  - Correspondence: Bertrice Shattuck Fulton [RFB's mother]-Auntie My [Myra Shattuck, Bertrice's sister], undated (Folder 39.12)
  - Correspondence: Auntie My [Myra Shattuck]-Ruth Fulton Benedict, undated (Folder 39.13)
  - Correspondence: Bob Freeman [RFB's brother-in-law]; Jo Fulton [RFB's cousin?]-Ruth Fulton Benedict, undated (Folder 39.14)
  - Correspondence: C.F. Middlebrook [RFB's cousin]-Ruth Fulton Benedict, undated (Folder 39.15)
  - Correspondence: Fred Fulton-Bertrice Shattuck, undated (Folder 39.16)
  - Stanley Benedict - Biography, undated (Folder 41.1)
  - Stanley Benedict - Death Certificate, undated (Folder 41.2)
  - Stanley Benedict - Obituaries, undated (Folder 41.3)
  - Stanley Benedict - Documents, Correspondence, undated (Folder 41.4)
  - RFB Correspondence re: Stanley Benedict, undated (Folder 41.5)
  - Correspondence re: Stanley Benedict Estate, undated (Folder 41.6)
  - Correspondence re: Stanley Benedict Estate, undated (Folder 41.7)
  - Deteriorated original materials, undated (Box 126)
- SERIES III. FINANCIAL DOCUMENTS
  - Publishing Contracts, undated (Folder 42.1)
  - Royalty Statements, undated (Folder 42.2)
  - Royalty Statements: Patterns of Culture, undated (Folder 42.3)
  - Employment Contracts: Columbia University, undated (Folder 42.4)
  - Columbia University Dept. of Anthropology Pay Scale, undated (Folder 42.5)
  - Columbia University Pay Orders, undated (Folder 42.6)
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS OF RUTH BENEDICT
  - JUVENILIA
    - Early Writing, undated (Folder 43.1)
    - A Blessed Incident, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.2)
    - The Future of the Horse, [1905]; (MS) (Folder 43.3)
    - The Greatest of These, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.4)
    - The Home of Evangeline, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.5)
    - How the Acadian Men Were Trapped, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.6)
    - The Last Bluff, undated; (TS) (Folder 43.7)
    - One Thanksgiving, [1905]; (MS) (Folder 43.8)
    - The Passing of Gabriel, [1910]; (MS) (Folder 43.9)
    - The Passion of Giving, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.10)
    - The Perseverance of Sir William Phipps, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.11)
    - The Sense of Symbolism, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.12)
    - The Sewing Society, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.13)
    - The Statue of Justice, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.14)
    - Untitled, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.15)
    - Wedding, A True Story, undated; (MS) (Folder 43.16)
  - DATE BOOKS, NOTEBOOKS, SCRAPBOOK, AND MISCELLANEOUS
    - Addresses and Names, undated (Folder 44.1)
    - Date Books, 1928, 1929 (Folder 44.2)
    - Date Books, 1930-1933 (Folder 44.3)
    - Date Books, 1934, 1935 (Folder 44.4)
    - Date Books, 1938, 1939 1941, 1942 (Folder 44.5)
    - Date Books, 1943-1945 (Folder 44.6)
    - Date Books, 1946, 1947 (Folder 44.7)
    - Rhyming Dictionary, undated (Folder 44.8)
    - The Bible in Pidgin English, or TOK BOI, undated (Folder 44.9)
    - Notebook - Art, undated (Folder 44.10)
    - Notebook - Sprig, i.e., Speedwriting, undated (Folder 44.11)
    - Notebook - Speedwriting, undated (Folder 44.12)
    - Scrapbook of Benedict's book reviews (first begun by Marie Eichelberger for RFB using clippings from RFB's files; probably does not contain all of RFB's reviews), undated (Box 45)
  - PUBLISHED POETRY (arranged alphabetically)
    - "And His Eyes Were Opened," AAW, pp. 187-188, (TS) (Folder 46.1)
    - "Annunciation," AAW, p. 475, (MS, TS) (Folder 46.2)
    - "Another Theseus," AAW, p. 478, (TS) (Folder 46.3)
    - "Burial." [AAW, p. 483], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.4)
    - "But the Son of Man ... " [AAW, p. 475], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.5)
    - "Counsel for Autumn." [AAW, p. 483], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.6)
    - "Countermand." [Poetry, Mar 1930], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.7)
    - "Death is the Citadel."The Nation, [20 Feb 1929], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.8)
    - "Discourse on Prayer."AAW, pp. 160-161, (TS) (Folder 46.9)
    - "Earth-Born." [Poetry, Jan 1928;AAW, p. 487], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.10)
    - "Eucharist." [The Nation, 26 Sep 1928;AAW, p. 479], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.11)
    - "For My Mother." [Poetry, Jan 1928], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.12)
    - "For Seed Bearing." [AAW, p. 71], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.13)
    - "For the Hour After Love." [Poetry, Jan 1928;AAW, p. 480], (TS) (Folder 46.14)
    - "I Shall Not Call." [Poetry, Jan 1928], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.15)
    - "In Praise of Uselessness." [AAW, p. 489], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.16)
    - "Intruder." [AAW, p. 474], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.17)
    - "Lift Up Your Heart." [Poetry, Jan 1928;AAW, p. 481], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.18)
    - "Love That Is Water." [Poetry, Mar 1930;AAW, p. 474], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.19)
    - "Miser's Wisdom,", undated; (TS) (Folder 46.20)
    - "Moth Wing." [AAW, p. 488], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.21)
    - "Myth." [AAW, p. 477], (TS) (Folder 46.22)
    - "New Year." [AAW, p. 56], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.23)
    - "November Burning" [draft of a possible book], (TS, MS) (Folder 46.24)
    - "November Burning." [Poetry, Mar 1930;AAW, p. 484], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.25)
    - "Our Task Is Laughter." [AAW, pp. 167-168], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.26)
    - "Price of Paradise." [AAW, p. 478], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.27)
    - "Resurgam." [AAW, p. 194], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.28)
    - "Resurrection of the Ghost." [AAW, p. 490], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.29)
    - "Ripeness Is All." [AAW, pp. 85-86], (MS, TS) (Folder 46.30)
    - "Rupert Brooke, 1914-1919." [AAW, p. 579], (TS, MS) (Folder 46.31)
    - "She Speaks to the Sea." [AAW, p. 487], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.32)
    - "Sight." [AAW, p. 70], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.33)
    - "Sleet Storm." [AAW, p. 482], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.34)
    - "Spiritus Tyrannus." [AAW, p. 486], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.35)
    - "There Is No Death." [AAW, p. 484], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.36)
    - "This Breath." [AAW, p. 474], undated; (TS) (Folder 46.37)
    - "This Gabriel." [AAW, p. 486], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.1)
    - "This Is My Body." [AAW, pp. 194-195], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.2)
    - "Toy Balloons." [Poetry, Aug 1926, under the pseudonym of Alice Singleton;AAW, p. 488], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.3)
    - "Unicorns At Sunrise." [Poetry, Mar 1930;AAW, p. 481], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.4)
    - "Unshadowed Pool." [Poetry, Mar 1930;AAW, p. 477], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.5)
    - "Ways Not Winds' Ways." [The Nation, 6 Dec 1933, published under Benedict's given name], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.6)
    - "Withdrawal." [AAW, p. 482], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.7)
    - "Words in Darkness." [AAW, p. 489], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.8)
    - "The Worst Is Not Our Anger." [AAW, p. 580], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.9)
    - "You Have Looked Upon the Sun." [AAW, p. 486], undated; (TS) (Folder 47.10)
  - UNPUBLISHED POETRY
    - Drafts and Fragments, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.11)
    - Alien, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.12)
    - And the Morning Stars Sang Together, (TS) (Folder 47.13)
    - Annihilation, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.14)
    - Apartment Notes, (MS) (Folder 47.15)
    - As a Dream, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.16)
    - At a Solemn Mummery, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.17)
    - At Last, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.18)
    - Awakening, (MS) (Folder 47.19)
    - Brook Turning, (TS) (Folder 47.20)
    - Consummation, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.21)
    - Damascus Road, (TS) (Folder 47.22)
    - Demarcation, (MS) (Folder 47.23)
    - Deridens, (MS) (Folder 47.24)
    - Disarmored, (TS) (Folder 47.25)
    - The Dream, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.26)
    - Flight, (TS) (Folder 47.27)
    - For a Certain Lover, (TS) (Folder 47.28)
    - For Faithfulness, (TS) (Folder 47.29)
    - For Holy Days, (TS) (Folder 47.30)
    - For One Who Loved My Canoe, (TS, MS) (Folder 47.31)
    - Fragment, (TS) (Folder 47.32)
    - Frostless Autumn, (MS) (Folder 47.33)
    - Fulfillment, (MS) (Folder 47.34)
    - Gloria Mundis, (TS) (Folder 47.35)
    - Grave Stele – Athens, (TS) (Folder 47.36)
    - Gray Pavements, (MS) (Folder 47.37)
    - I Have Content More in Your Loveliness, (TS) (Folder 48.1)
    - In Parables, (TS) (Folder 48.2)
    - In Praise of Life, (TS) (Folder 48.3)
    - Indemnity, (MS) (Folder 48.4)
    - Indian-Pipes, (TS) (Folder 48.5)
    - Indian Summer, (MS) (Folder 48.6)
    - Iridescent Glass from Etruria, (TS) (Folder 48.7)
    - The Kiss, (MS) (Folder 48.8)
    - The Little Room, (MS) (Folder 48.9)
    - Monk of Ariège, (TS) (Folder 48.10)
    - The Moon New Seen, (TS) (Folder 48.11)
    - Never Go Lonely, (TS) (Folder 48.12)
    - Ourselves, (TS) (Folder 48.13)
    - Parlor Car-Santa Fe, (TS) (Folder 48.14)
    - Pool, (TS) (Folder 48.15)
    - Preference, (TS) (Folder 48.16)
    - Profit of Dreams, (TS) (Folder 48.17)
    - A Psalm, (MS) (Folder 48.18)
    - Rhyme, (MS) (Folder 48.19)
    - Riders of the Wind, (TS) (Folder 48.20)
    - The Sacrilege, (TS) (Folder 48.21)
    - Sepulchre, (TS) (Folder 48.22)
    - Siren's Song, (TS, MS) (Folder 48.23)
    - Song, (TS) (Folder 48.24)
    - Song for Lovers, (TS) (Folder 48.25)
    - South Wind, (TS) (Folder 48.26)
    - Swimming, (TS, MS) (Folder 48.27)
    - Tempest, (MS) (Folder 48.28)
    - To M.M. With These Verses, (TS) (Folder 48.29)
    - Too Great Has Been the Tension of My Cloud, (TS) (Folder 48.30)
    - Tree Shadows, (TS) (Folder 48.31)
    - Turn of the River Tide, (TS) (Folder 48.32)
    - Verses For One Dancing, (TS, MS) (Folder 48.33)
    - Vision, (MS) (Folder 48.34)
    - Woman-Christ, (MS) (Folder 48.35)
    - The Woman to Her Dead Husband, (TS, MS) (Folder 48.36)
    - Wood Paths, (TS) (Folder 48.37)
  - PUBLISHED PROSE
    - Anthropology and the Humanities [American Anthropologist, vol. 50 (address as retiring president)], 1948 (Folder 49.1)
    - Anthropology in Your Life [Vassar Alumnae Magazine, vol. 32], 1946 (Folder 49.2)
    - The Bond of Fellowship [undated ms. published in AAW], [circa 1942] (Folder 49.3)
    - Continuities and Discontinuities in Cultural Conditioning[Psychiatry, vol. 1], 1938 (Folder 49.4)
    - Boas' Contributions to Ethnology, 1943 (Folder 49.5)
    - Dress [Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, vol. 5], 1931 (Folder 49.6)
    - Editorial on War [American Scholar, vol. 12], 1942 (Folder 49.7)
    - The Educational Process: A Comparative Note[Mental Health in the Classroom, 13th yearbook], [1940] (Folder 49.8)
    - Ideologies in the Light of Comparative Data [unpublished ms. excerpted in AAW], [circa 1941-1942] (Folder 49.9)
    - In Henry's Backyard, [1948]; (carbon ts.) (Folder 49.10)
    - Let's Get Rid of Prejudice [National Parent-Teacher Magazine, vol. 40], 1946 (Folder 49.11)
    - Marital Property Rights in a Bilateral Society - notes [American Anthropologist, vol. 38], [1936] (Folder 49.12)
    - Natural History of War [unpublished ms. published in AAW], [1939] (Folder 49.13)
    - Post-War Race Prejudice [unpublished ms. published in AAW], [circa 1947] (Folder 49.14)
    - Privileged Classes: An Anthropological Problem [Frontiers of Democracy, vol. 7], [1941] (Folder 49.15)
    - Foreword to Race: Science and Politics (second ed.), [1943] (Folder 49.16)
    - Preface to Race and Cultural Politics (second ed.) (Folder 49.17)
    - Racism is Vulnerable [English Journal, vol. 35], 1946 (Folder 49.19)
    - San Idlefonso Collection, [1933] (Folder 49.20)
    - Some Comparative Data on Culture and Personality with Reference to the Promotion of Mental Health [American Association for the Advancement of Science, no. 9], 1939 (Folder 49.21)
    - Teachers and the Hatch Act [Frontiers of Democracy, vol. 8], 1942 (Folder 49.22)
    - Transmitting Our Democratic Heritage in the Schools [American Journal of Sociology, v. 48], [1943] (Folder 49.23)
    - The Uses of Cannibalism [unpub. ms. publ. in AAW], [circa 1925] (Folder 49.24)
    - The Viking Fund [American Anthropologist, vol. 49], 1947 (Folder 49.25)
    - We Can't Afford Race Prejudice [Frontiers of Democracy, vol. 9], 1942 (Folder 49.26)
  - THE CHRYSANTHEMUM AND THE SWORD (1946)
    - Japanese National Character, by Ruth Benedict (1947)[speech given at Columbia University], undated (Folder 50.1)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword - Reviews, undated (Folder 50.2)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword - Royalty Statements, undated (Folder 50.3)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 1, undated (Folder 50.4)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 2, undated (Folder 50.5)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 3, undated (Folder 50.6)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 4, undated (Folder 50.7)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 5, undated (Folder 50.8)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 6, undated (Folder 50.9)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 7, undated (Folder 50.10)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 8, undated (Folder 50.11)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 9, undated (Folder 50.12)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 10, undated (Folder 50.13)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 11, undated (Folder 50.14)
    - The Chrysanthemum and the Sword, Chapter 12, undated (Folder 50.15)